Shreekant Kembhavi

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Harrow, United Kingdom | +44 7488 508 999 | | shreekant.pk@gmail.com | me.shree.uk

SUMMARY

Dedicated to optimization, experienced DevOps Engineer understands the melding of operations and development to quickly deliver code to customers. Has experience with the Cloud and monitoring processes as well as DevOps development in Windows Mac and Linux systems. Brings a master's degree in Information Technology and experience working as a DevOps Engineer since shortly after the concept was introduced.

EDUCATION

Master's in Information Technology – 2:1 (2012) The University of Nottingham, United Kingdom

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Engineering – First Class (2010) B.N.M. Institute of Technology, Bangalore, India

Diploma in Information Science and Technology – First Class (2006) N.V. Polytechnic, Kalaburagi, India

CORE QUALIFICATION

- Over 12 years of work experience as DevOps Engineer coupling with 7 years of computer science education.
- Infrastructure-As-Code using Terraform.
- Part of building Kubernetes platform to deploy Security tools.
- Usage of cloud including Azure and AWS, Also familiar with Cloud Foundry and OpenStack.
- Monitoring using tools like Datadog, AppDynamics, Dynatrace, Azure Monitoring service.
- Migrating on premise application to Cloud.
- Strong use of Interpreted Languages including Python.
- Build and maintain CI/CD system using Jenkins and Azure DevOps.
- Facility with development methodologies including Agile and Kanban.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cloud Engineer | (Jan 2023 - Till Date) Cisco Systems, London, United Kingdom

- Design and automate secure Kubernetes based container orchestration platform to allow tenants to deploy their Security applications used by internal and external users.
- Build the platform using Terraform, AWS, Jenkins, Cluster API, Docker, Python, Openstack etc.
- Build and deploy features used by tenants.
- Use Datadog/AppDynamics for monitoring the platform.

Senior DevOps Engineer | (Feb 2021 - Dec 2022) Nationwide Building Society, London, United Kingdom

- Build the cloud infrastructure for payments that has connectivity to on-premise and third party tools for faster payments.
- Infrastructure-As-Code using Terraform on AWS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Kubernetes, Terraform,
Jenkins, Helm, Docker, FluxCD,
Harness, AppDynamics,
Dynatrace, AWS, Python,
Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud,
GIT, Openstack, Linux, Docker,
Jira, Postman

CERTIFICATIONS

Hashicorp Certified Terraform Associate (Expires Sept 2023)

Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate (Expires June 2022)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate (Expires May 2023)

- Design and build the CICD system using Jenkins Configuration as Code which deploys microservices on multiple environment.
- Build and maintain infrastructure on Kubernetes.
- Maintain the infrastructure including GitHub, Jenkins, SonarQube.
- Work on Kanban methodology.

Tech Architecture Delivery Specialist | (July 2019 - Feb 2021)

Accenture, London, United Kingdom

- Involved in maintaining infrastructure including
 Kubernetes on Azure Cloud, Maintaining repositories.
- Release of product using Azure DevOps.
- Migration of tools to Azure DevOps.
- Involved in creating pipelines for CI/CD in Azure DevOps.
- Architecting the infrastructure to fit the application in AWS and Azure.

DevOps Engineer | (July 2017 - July 2019) SAP Labs, Bangalore, India

- Onboarding customers on SAP Leonardo IoT Platform on Cloud foundry.
- Minimizing the tasks using REST API using postman.
- Configured Dynatrace for monitoring IoT Applications and infrastructure including HANA database.
- Integrated multiple tools into CICD process.

Release Engineer | (Nov 2016 - July 2017) Oracle, Bangalore, India

- Release development for Oracle Fusion HCM cloud.
- Involved in applying weekly and monthly patch bundles in the pods.

Software Engineer | (June 2014 - Nov 2016)

Cisco, Bangalore, India

Vendors: Randstad India Limited and Volen softwares

- Part of central DevOps team to provide the platform to build and test features in set top box and virtual set top boxes.
- Usage of tools including Jenkins, Opsnstack, Mantis, Shinken, Python, IBM ClearCase, Git/Gerrit etc.

Freelance | (Jan 2013 - May 2014)

 Business development in our construction company including requirement analysis, web development marketing etc.